Oscar Forner Martinez

I am a software engineer with experience in all phases of the development process with special focus on delivering quality software to the costumers. I have experience in a diversity of projects ranging from a RESTful API processing thousands of requests per second, through compilers to video processing pipelines.

You can use an interactive version of my CV by running: docker run -it maitesin/resume

Experience

June 2018

Senior Backend Software Engineer at GlobalSign

- Present

As part of my duties in GlobalSign I implemented new functionalities in the **High Performance Platform** that serve thousands of certificates per second, and I took care of the migration of backend storage from **MongoDB** to **PostgreSQL**.

Moreover, implemented a prototype of the system used in production running in **Kubernetes** to test the feasibility of a future migration. As a side project I developed an **static analysis** tool to enforce the code style used in the company.

I mentored multiple new-hires and had a highly involved role in the hiring process.

Sept. 2016 - June 2018

Software Engineer at VCA Technology

During my time at VCA Technology I created a **network library** that allows the user to interact with **Boost ASIO** through the **std::stream** interface, added **authentication** to the system, and designed the **configuration migration process**.

In addition, I improved the in-house **toolchain** to use **clang-tidy** for the linting of our code and I lead the usage of **continuous integration** in order to improve the product delivered to the customer, and to reduce the time to market.

April 2015

Software Developer at Programming Research

- Sept. 2016

I worked in two projects during my time at Programming Research.

- -Static analysis of code: Checks if the code has some patterns that have an undefined behaviour, unspecified in the Standard, and/or implementation-defined.
- -Dataflow analysis of code: Checks the complexity of methods, pointer problems, memory handling, etc.

July 2013

Software Engineer at European Bioinformatics Institute

- Apr. 2015

One of my duties was to create a RESTful service to allow users to query for information about multiprotein complexes.

In addition, I developed an algorithm to cluster biological information from proteins.

2013-Present

Open Source

I am actively contributing to open source projects that I find interesting, and useful. Some of my contributions can be found in my **GitHub profile**.

To name some, ARM C Compiler (ACC) is a self-hosting compiler for C in the ARM architecture, Interactive CV built using Rust and Docker, and a Prefix Tree Comparison to compare the performance of *Trie* and *Radix Tree*.

Education

2010-2013 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Advanced Data Structures, Compilers and Interpreters and Distributed Systems

2006-2010 Associate Degree in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Operating Systems, Real Time Operating Systems and Embedded Systems

Programming Languages

C++ 5 years of experience using *Modern C*++ and *Boost*.

Python 5 years of experience.

C 4 years of experience.

Go 3 year of experience.

Technical Skills

Build CMake, Meson, Make and Ninja.

CI GitLab-CI, Jenkins, Bamboo and Travis.

Databases MongoDB, PostgreSQL, CockroachDB, MariaDB, SQLite and MySQL.

Analysis Golint, Go vet, Perf, Clang-sanitizer and Valgrind.

Orchestra- Kubernetes, Helm and Docker compose.

tion

Message Bro-

RabbitMQ and Kafka.

ker

Operating Systems

GNU/Linux, MacOS, FreeBSD and OpenBSD.

Languages

Spanish Native

English Fluent

oscar.forner.martinez@gmail.com +44 (0)75 96944383

Blog: https://oscarforner.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarforner

GitHub: https://github.com/maitesin